Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Kathryn and today we have a great lesson for you about traveling.
我是Kathryn，今天我们有一节关于旅行的精彩课程。
That's right.
没错。
You know, we have taken a look at previous lessons where you can buy a ticket, how to
你知道，我们之前看过一些课程，教你如何买票、如何
book a flight, what to do at the airport, but now we are going to see what we can do
预订航班、在机场该做什么，但现在我们要看看如果
if our flight gets canceled.
我们的航班被取消了该怎么办。
Okay, this is not a fun situation, but hopefully with our help you'll be able to understand
好吧，这可不是什么有趣的情况，但希望在我们的帮助下，你能理解
what these messages are about flights that are canceled or delayed.
这些关于航班取消或延误的信息。
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue.
那么，让我们来听听今天的对话。
Good afternoon, sir.
下午好，先生。
May I please see your passport and reservation?
请出示您的护照和预订信息好吗？
Here you go.
给你。
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
哦，抱歉，先生。
This flight has been canceled due to some mechanical problems.
这个航班因为一些机械问题被取消了。
Canceled?
取消了？
What am I supposed to do now?
那我该怎么办？
We apologize for any inconveniences that may be caused by this.
我们为由此可能造成的不便表示歉意。
If your flight is urgent, I could put you on a waiting list for another flight this
如果您的航班很紧急，我可以把您列入今晚另一个航班的
evening, but it's on a first come, first serve basis.
候补名单，但这是按先到先得的原则。
So there's no guarantee you'll be able to take that flight.
所以不能保证您能坐上那个航班。
What are my other options?
我还有其他选择吗？
Well, if you can wait until tomorrow, we will put you up in a hotel for today and you can
嗯，如果您能等到明天，我们今天会为您安排酒店住宿，您可以
take the scheduled flight for tomorrow morning.
乘坐明天早上预定的航班。
That's fine.
那好吧。
I'll do that then.
我就这么办。
Thank you for your understanding, sir.
感谢您的理解，先生。
I'll book your flight now.
我现在就为您预订航班。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now it's time for us to go into Language Takeaway.
现在是时候进入“语言要点”环节了。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, in Language Takeaway today, we have about four words or phrases.
好的，在今天的“语言要点”中，我们有大约四个单词或短语。
The first one is the reason for this cancellation.
第一个是这次取消的原因。
The reason is mechanical problems.
原因是机械问题。
That's right.
没错。
She said that the airplane has some mechanical problems and that's why the flight is canceled.
她说飞机有一些机械问题，所以航班被取消了。
So the key here is mechanical.
所以这里的关键词是“机械的”。
Mechanical meaning like related to machines, right?
“机械的”意思是与机器相关的，对吧？
All right, so something that's a mechanical problem has to do with the actual structure
好的，所以机械问题与飞机的实际结构
of the plane.
有关。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, maybe something is wrong with the wings or maybe something is wrong with
例如，可能是机翼有问题，或者
the engines, some type of problem that has to do with the mechanics of the machine.
引擎有问题，一些与机器机械方面有关的问题。
Right.
对。
And obviously, if you have a problem with the wings or the wheels or the engine, you
显然，如果机翼、轮子或引擎有问题，你
don't want to fly that plane.
可不想坐那架飞机。
That's right.
没错。
So this caused the canceled flight.
所以这导致了航班取消。
Now after that, we heard this word, we apologize for any inconveniences.
之后，我们听到了这个词，“我们为任何不便表示歉意”。
What's an inconvenience, Marco?
Marco，“不便”是什么意思？
That's right.
没错。
Well, obviously, I planned to take this flight, let's say Tuesday at 8 a.m. and if the flight
嗯，显然，我计划坐这趟航班，比如周二早上8点，如果航班
is canceled, that means I have to wait an hour or three hours or maybe for the next
被取消，那就意味着我得等一个小时、三个小时，或者可能等到
day.
第二天。
So it's an inconvenience.
所以这就是不便。
It means it's not convenient for me.
意思是它对我来说不方便。
It causes me some trouble.
它给我带来了一些麻烦。
All right, so something that is inconvenient causes problems or causes trouble.
好的，所以不方便的事情会引起问题或麻烦。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, you have this late flight or canceled flight, that's an inconvenience.
例如，你遇到晚点或取消的航班，这就是不便。
But also, small things can be inconvenient as well.
但小事也可能不方便。
Like I want to go home at 5.
比如我想5点回家。
Unfortunately, I have to write this report.
不幸的是，我得写这份报告。
It's very inconvenient.
这非常不方便。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe you have a doctor's appointment tomorrow at 12, but you also have a meeting at your
所以也许你明天12点有医生预约，但你在
work so it's inconvenient, these two dates.
工作单位也有会议，所以这两个时间冲突，很不方便。
All right, they cause problems for each other.
好的，它们互相造成问题。
So after that, the service person says if your flight is urgent, I can put you on a
之后，服务人员说如果您的航班很紧急，我可以把您列入
waiting list.
候补名单。
Right.
对。
Waiting list.
候补名单。
So this is another important phrase to understand when we're talking about canceled flights.
所以这是另一个重要短语，当我们谈论取消的航班时需要理解。
That's right.
没错。
We usually get put on a waiting list and it's basically a list with everyone's names where
我们通常会被列入候补名单，这基本上是一个包含所有人名字的名单，
you are waiting for the next available flight or you're waiting to be able to have the service
你在等待下一个可用的航班，或者你在等待能够获得
provided.
服务。
All right, so you can have a waiting list at an airport like here, but you can also
好的，所以像这里一样，机场可以有候补名单，但
have a waiting list at a restaurant, right?
餐厅也可以有候补名单，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Restaurants are super popular and you got to get on a waiting list.
餐厅非常火爆，你得排队等位。
So can I put my name on the waiting list?
那我能把名字加到等位名单上吗？
That means can you call me when there's a free table?
意思是，有位子的时候你能打电话通知我吗？
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So even though we are on this waiting list, it doesn't mean that we are guaranteed to
所以，即使我们在候补名单上，也不代表我们一定能
be able to take this flight this evening.
赶上今晚的航班。
So there is no guarantee.
所以没有保证。
All right, this guarantee, this is an important thing to talk about because a guarantee is
好的，这个“保证”是个重要话题，因为保证
something that means that we will definitely get a later flight.
意味着我们肯定能坐上后续航班。
Yeah, we promise.
是的，我们承诺。
We promise.
我们承诺。
So you often see the word guarantee in advertisements.
所以你经常在广告中看到“保证”这个词。
For example, this TV has a six month guarantee.
比如，这台电视有六个月的保修期。
So we guarantee it won't break.
所以我们保证它不会坏。
If it does, we will fix it.
如果坏了，我们会修好。
But no guarantee means that we can't promise.
但“没有保证”意味着我们不能承诺。
We don't promise.
我们不承诺。
So it's possible that you won't get a flight.
所以你可能坐不上航班。
So for example, if you buy a new car, the manufacturer will guarantee that it's in good
比如，如果你买一辆新车，制造商将保证它状态良好
condition and it won't break down.
并且不会出故障。
But if you buy a used car, it's unlikely that they will give you that same guarantee.
但如果你买一辆二手车，他们不太可能给你同样的保证。
No, that's right.
对，没错。
They cannot promise it because they don't know.
他们不能承诺，因为他们不知道。
Exactly.
正是。
All right, so a lot of words and phrases there.
好了，这里有很多单词和短语。
Why don't we go back and listen to our dialogue again.
我们不如回去再听一遍对话。
Good afternoon, sir.
下午好，先生。
May I please see your passport and reservation?
请出示您的护照和预订信息好吗？
Here you go.
给您。
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
哦，抱歉，先生。
This flight has been canceled due to some mechanical problems.
这趟航班因机械故障被取消了。
Canceled?
取消了？
What am I supposed to do now?
我现在该怎么办？
We apologize for any inconveniences that may be caused by this.
我们为此可能造成的不便深表歉意。
If your flight is urgent, I could put you on a waiting list for another flight this
如果您的航班很紧急，我可以把您列入今晚另一趟航班的
evening.
候补名单。
But it's on a first come first serve basis.
但这是按先到先得的原则。
So there's no guarantee you'll be able to take that flight.
所以不能保证您能坐上那趟航班。
What are my other options?
我还有其他选择吗？
Well, if you can wait until tomorrow, we will put you up in a hotel for today.
嗯，如果您能等到明天，我们今晚会为您安排酒店住宿。
And you can take the scheduled flight for tomorrow morning.
您可以乘坐明天早上的定期航班。
That's fine.
那行。
I'll do that then.
我就这么办吧。
Thank you for your understanding, sir.
感谢您的理解，先生。
I'll book your flight now.
我现在就为您预订航班。
All right, so now let's take a look at three key phrases that we have prepared for you
好了，现在让我们看看我们为你们准备的三个关键短语
on Fluency Builder.
在流利度提升部分。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
Okay, so the first phrase we have here is a very important one.
好的，我们这里的第一个短语非常重要。
This tells us about the cause of the problem.
它告诉我们问题的原因。
The service person said, I'm sorry, sir.
服务人员说：“抱歉，先生。
This flight has been canceled due to some mechanical problems.
这趟航班因机械故障被取消了。”
Right.
对。
So this phrase due to basically is saying because of, right?
所以这个短语“due to”基本上就是“because of”的意思，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So this flight has been canceled because of mechanical problems.
所以这趟航班因机械故障被取消了。
And remember this due is D-U-E.
记住这个“due”是D-U-E。
That's right.
没错。
D-U-E.
D-U-E。
So I think it's kind of a nicer or more formal way of saying because of or the reason is.
所以我认为这是“because of”或“the reason is”的一种更优雅或更正式的说法。
Exactly.
正是。
So for example, the picnic has been canceled due to bad weather.
比如，野餐因天气不好被取消了。
So it sounds a lot more professional, a lot more formal than if you say because of bad
这听起来比说“because of bad weather”更专业、更正式。
weather.
天气。
All right.
好的。
So just remember here due to indicates the cause or the reason.
所以记住，“due to”表示原因或理由。
It's like saying because.
就像说“because”。
All right.
好的。
Now, when we were talking about the flights, we said that we are on the waiting list, but
现在，当我们谈论航班时，我们说我们在候补名单上，但
in order to catch this flight, they are going to take people on a first come first served
为了赶上这趟航班，他们会按先到先得的原则
basis.
安排乘客。
All right.
好的。
First come first served.
先到先得。
Now, this is again a very common phrase.
这也是一个非常常见的短语。
It's related to that waiting list thing we were talking about.
它和我们之前讨论的候补名单有关。
If you have a waiting list, usually the waiting list is first come first serve.
如果你有候补名单，通常候补名单是按先到先得的原则。
So I could say, am I guaranteed a spot?
所以我可以问：“我能保证有位子吗？”
And you could say, well.
你可以说：“嗯，
It's first come first serve.
这是先到先得。”
Maybe, maybe not.
也许能，也许不能。
Right.
对。
If I'm number one on the list, I will probably get a seat.
如果我在名单上排第一，我可能就能有个座位。
But if I'm number 30, probably not.
但如果我排第30，可能就没戏了。
So what we mean by it is that we don't give priority to anyone.
所以我们说的意思是，我们不优先对待任何人。
We don't say, oh, you are more important or you're not.
我们不会说，哦，你更重要或者你不重要。
Whoever comes first gets it.
谁先来谁就得到它。
All right.
好的。
So if I come to the restaurant at five o'clock, I get to sit first.
所以如果我五点来到餐厅，我就先坐下。
But if you come at 510, you're next.
但如果你五点十分来，你就排在我后面。
And after you, 530.
你之后，是五点半的人。
So it's first come first serve.
所以这就是先到先得。
It depends on when you arrive.
这取决于你到达的时间。
That's right.
没错。
So obviously this wasn't convenient for us.
所以显然这对我们来说不方便。
So we are going to wait until tomorrow.
所以我们打算等到明天。
But the airline will put us up in a hotel.
但航空公司会安排我们住酒店。
We will put you up in a hotel.
我们会安排你住酒店。
All right.
好的。
So let's take this as a phrase because we all know what a hotel is.
所以我们把这个当作一个短语，因为大家都知道酒店是什么。
It's a place where you stay when you're on holiday or business.
酒店是你度假或出差时住的地方。
But to put someone up, what exactly does this mean?
但“put someone up”到底是什么意思呢？
Basically you are paying for that person to stay at that hotel.
基本上就是你为那个人支付住酒店的费用。
And you made the reservation and you're going to pay for the room.
而且你做了预订，并会支付房间费用。
So I will put you up means I will pay for your room at a hotel.
所以“I will put you up”意思是我会支付你在酒店的房间费用。
Right.
对。
And it's usually only for accommodation for a hotel.
而且通常只指酒店住宿。
You can't say I will put you up for a meal.
你不能说“I will put you up for a meal”。
No.
不行。
But you can say I'll put you up at my house, which means I will let you stay the night
但你可以说“I'll put you up at my house”，意思是我让你在我家过夜，
at my house.
在我家。
So not food, but actually sleeping.
所以不是食物，而是睡觉。
Right.
对。
So it usually involves sleeping.
所以通常涉及睡觉。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, you could say he's coming to our hometown for the wedding.
比如，你可以说他要来我们家乡参加婚礼。
I will put him up at my house.
我会安排他住在我家。
Right.
对。
Or if your company sent you to Japan, you say my company put me up at the Hyatt Hotel.
或者如果你的公司派你去日本，你可以说我的公司安排我住在凯悦酒店。
Oh, fancy.
哦，真高级。
Nice.
不错。
All right.
好的。
So that's all the phrases we have for you.
这就是我们为你准备的所有短语。
Let's listen to our dialogue one last time.
让我们最后听一遍对话。
Good afternoon, sir.
下午好，先生。
May I please see your passport and reservation?
请出示您的护照和预订信息好吗？
Here you go.
给你。
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
哦，对不起，先生。
This flight has been canceled due to some mechanical problems.
这趟航班因机械故障被取消了。
Canceled?
取消了？
What am I supposed to do now?
我现在该怎么办？
We apologize for any inconveniences that may be caused by this.
我们为由此可能造成的不便表示歉意。
If your flight is urgent, I could put you on a waiting list for another flight this
如果您的航班很紧急，我可以把您列入今晚另一趟航班的候补名单，
evening.
今晚的。
But it's on a first come, first serve basis.
但这是按先到先得的原则。
So there's no guarantee you'll be able to take that flight.
所以不能保证您能坐上那趟航班。
What are my other options?
我还有其他选择吗？
Well, if you can wait until tomorrow, we will put you up in a hotel for today.
嗯，如果您能等到明天，我们今天会安排您住酒店。
And you can take the scheduled flight for tomorrow morning.
您可以乘坐明天早上的定期航班。
That's fine.
好的。
I'll do that then.
那我就这么办吧。
Thank you for your understanding, sir.
感谢您的理解，先生。
I'll book your flight now.
我现在就为您预订航班。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So talking about canceled flights, usually it's due to bad weather.
说到航班取消，通常是因为天气不好。
And usually you can catch another flight soon.
而且通常你很快就能赶上另一趟航班。
But sometimes you do have these problems.
但有时确实会遇到这些问题。
Like when there was the whole 9-11 thing, I think a lot of flights were canceled or
比如在9·11事件期间，我想很多航班都被取消了，或者
the volcano that erupted and European flights were grounded for a long time.
火山爆发导致欧洲航班长时间停飞。
Yes, that's right.
是的，没错。
So sometimes there are natural disasters.
所以有时是自然灾害。
Sometimes there are man-made disasters.
有时是人祸。
But you actually said a very interesting word there and something that I think people who
但你刚才说了一个很有趣的词，我觉得学习这个的人
are learning about this should definitely study.
应该好好研究一下。
The word is grounded.
这个词是“grounded”。
A flight has been grounded.
航班被停飞了。
Yes.
是的。
That means that the airplane will stay on the ground.
意思是飞机将停在地面上。
It means the plane will not fly.
意思是飞机不会起飞。
OK.
好的。
So when planes are grounded because of bad weather or because of a natural disaster like
所以当飞机因恶劣天气或自然灾害（比如火山爆发）而停飞时，
a volcano, it's a very serious situation because the people who are going to fly can't now.
情况会非常严重，因为原本要坐飞机的人现在走不了了。
Now in our dialogue, we saw that they handled it, the airline handled it very, very well.
在我们的对话中，我们看到他们处理得很好，航空公司处理得非常非常好。
But I think this is a very rare case.
但我觉得这是非常罕见的情况。
You've had flights canceled before.
你之前遇到过航班取消。
How did they handle it?
他们是怎么处理的？
I have.
我遇到过。
I've had two or three flights canceled one time because of a blizzard.
我有过两三次航班取消，有一次是因为暴风雪。
So all flights were grounded.
所以所有航班都停飞了。
The weather was very bad, very dangerous.
天气非常糟糕，非常危险。
And the airline company said, well, we're sorry.
然后航空公司说，嗯，我们很抱歉。
There are no more flights.
没有更多航班了。
But if you come back tomorrow, we can help you.
但如果你明天再来，我们可以帮你。
And I was very lucky because they did not give me a hotel.
我很幸运，因为他们没有给我安排酒店。
They did not put me up in a hotel.
他们没有给我安排住宿。
But I was staying with a friend.
但我当时住在朋友那里。
So my friends put me up at her house.
所以我朋友让我住在她家。
But the other time the flight was canceled, the airline put me on a flight from another
但另一次航班取消时，航空公司把我安排到了另一家
company, another airline company.
航空公司的航班上。
And so sometimes they can do that where they have a relationship with another airline company,
所以有时候他们可以这样做，如果和另一家航空公司有关系的话，
they can do that.
他们就能做到。
So usually they do try to handle it relatively well.
所以通常他们确实会尽量处理得相对好一些。
But I've heard sometimes that they are not very understanding or very sympathetic to
但我听说有时候他们对自己造成的
the inconvenience they cause.
不便并不太理解或同情。
Definitely.
确实。
And I think the worst is when it's bad weather because everyone's angry.
我觉得最糟糕的是天气不好的时候，因为每个人都很生气。
And all the customers need to go somewhere, but they can't because there are no flights.
所有乘客都需要去某个地方，但他们去不了，因为没有航班。
And so the people who are working for the airlines get very frustrated or upset.
所以航空公司的工作人员会变得非常沮丧或烦躁。
Right.
没错。
Because basically it's not their fault.
因为基本上这不是他们的错。
It's not their fault.
不是他们的错。
There's bad weather.
是天气不好。
So there's not really much compensation the company can give you.
所以公司能给你的补偿其实不多。
No, definitely not.
不，确实不多。
Not really their fault.
真不是他们的错。
But it's hard not to get frustrated because you want to go home, you're tired, you don't
但很难不感到沮丧，因为你想回家，你很累，你不想
want to pay for another night in a hotel.
再付一晚酒店的钱。
So I can understand both sides.
所以我能理解双方。
Right.
没错。
Well, it's an interesting topic and I'm sure many of our listeners who have traveled have
嗯，这是个有趣的话题，我相信很多旅行过的听众都
had a flight delayed or canceled.
遇到过航班延误或取消。
So you can come to our website and share your story with us.
所以你可以来我们的网站分享你的故事。
And of course, if you have any questions or comments.
当然，如果你有任何问题或评论。
You can find us at EnglishPod.com.
你可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
We hope to see you all there.
我们希望能在那里见到大家。
All right.
好了。
Bye.
再见。